Today I'm going to speak to you
سأحدثكم اليوم
about the last 30 years of architectural history.
عن 30 عاما من تاريخ الهندسة.
That's a lot to pack into 18 minutes.
هذا أمر كبير جدا لألخصه في 18 دقيقة.
It's a complex topic,
إنه موضوع معقد،
so we're just going to dive right in at a complex place:
لذلك فإننا سنتوجه مباشرة إلى مكان معقد:
New Jersey.
إلى نيو جيرسي،
Because 30 years ago, I'm from Jersey,
لأنه منذ 30 سنة، أنا من نيوجيرسي،
and I was six, and I lived there in my parents' house
كنت في السادسة من عمري، وكنت أعيش هناك مع والدي
in a town called Livingston,
في مدينة تدعى ليفينغستون،
and this was my childhood bedroom.
وكانت هذه غرفة نومي.
Around the corner from my bedroom
عند زاوية غرفتي
was the bathroom that I used to share with my sister.
كان هناك حمام أتقاسمه مع أختي.
And in between my bedroom and the bathroom
وبين غرفتي والحمام
was a balcony that overlooked the family room.
كانت هناك شرفة تطل على غرفة المعيشة.
And that's where everyone would hang out and watch TV,
وهناك حيث كان يجتمع الجميع لمشاهدة التلفاز،
so that every time that I walked from my bedroom to the bathroom,
لذلك فإنه في كل مرة أذهب من غرفتي إلى الحمام،
everyone would see me,
كان الجميع يراني،
and every time I took a shower and would come back in a towel,
وفي كل مرة أستحم وأخرج ملتحفا فوطتي،
everyone would see me.
كان الجميع يراني.
And I looked like this.
كنت أبدو هكذا.
I was awkward,
كنت أحس بالغرابة،
insecure, and I hated it.
وعدم الأمان، فكنت أكره هذا الشعور.
I hated that walk, I hated that balcony,
كنت أكره ذلك الممشى، تلك الشرفة،
I hated that room, and I hated that house.
كنت أكره تلك الغرفة، وذلك البيت.
And that's architecture.
وتلك هي الهندسة المعمارية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Done.
انتهى.
That feeling, those emotions that I felt,
ذلك الشعور، تلك الأحاسيس التي أحسها،
that's the power of architecture,
تلك هي قوة الهندسة المعمارية،
because architecture is not about math and it's not about zoning,
لأن الهندسة المعمارية ليست رياضيات وتقسيما.
it's about those visceral, emotional connections
بل هي تلك التقاطعات الحسية المشحونة
that we feel to the places that we occupy.
التي نحسها في الأماكن التي نشغلها.
And it's no surprise that we feel that way,
ولا غرابة في أننا نحس على هذا النحو،
because according to the EPA,
لأنه بحسب وكالة حماية البيئة،
Americans spend 90 percent of their time indoors.
فإن الأمريكيين يقضون 90 في المئة من أوقاتهم في الداخل.
That's 90 percent of our time surrounded by architecture.
يعني 90 في المئة من أوقاتنا ونحن محاطون بالهندسة.
That's huge.
هذا أمر هائل.
That means that architecture is shaping us in ways that we didn't even realize.
ما يعني أن الهندسة تحدد من نكون بطرق لم نكن نعيها بالأساس،
That makes us a little bit gullible and very, very predictable.
ما يجعلنا سذجا شيئا ما، ويمكن التنبؤ بما نريد بسهولة جدا.
It means that when I show you a building like this,
هذا يعني أنه حين أريكم مبنى كهذا،
I know what you think:
أعلم بماذا ستفكرون:
You think "power" and "stability" and "democracy."
ستفكرون ب" القوة' و'الاستقرار" و"الديمقراطية."
And I know you think that because it's based on a building
وأعرف أنكم تفكرون على هذا النحو لأنه مبني على أساس بناء
that was build 2,500 years ago by the Greeks.
أسس منذ 2500 سنت خلت من طرف اليونانيين.
This is a trick.
هذه هي الخدعة.
This is a trigger that architects use
هذا هو المحفز الذي يستعمله المهندسون
to get you to create an emotional connection
لكي يخلقوا لديكم ذلك الرابط العاطفي
to the forms that we build our buildings out of.
مع الأشكال التي نبني بها البنايات.
It's a predictable emotional connection,
إنه رابط عاطفي متوقع،
and we've been using this trick for a long, long time.
وقد استعملناه منذ زمن طويل جدا.
We used it [200] years ago to build banks.
استعملناه منذ 200 سنة لبناء الأبناك.
We used it in the 19th century to build art museums.
استعملناه في القرن 19 لبناء المتاحف الفنية.
And in the 20th century in America,
وفي القرن ال20 في الولايات المتحدة الأمريكية،
we used it to build houses.
استعملناه لبناء المنازل.
And look at these solid, stable little soldiers
أنظروا إلى هؤلاء الجنود اليافعين المستقرين وذوي الصلابة،
facing the ocean and keeping away the elements.
المواجهين للمحيط ليبعدوا الأخطار،
This is really, really useful,
هذا أمر مفيد جدا.
because building things is terrifying.
لأن بناء الأشياء أمر مرعب.
It's expensive, it takes a long time, and it's very complicated.
فهو مكلف، ويتطلب وقتا طويلا، كما أنه معقد جدا،
And the people that build things --
ومن يقوم ببناء هذه الأشياء--
developers and governments --
المطورون والحكومات--
they're naturally afraid of innovation,
يخافون بشكل طبيعي من الابتكار،
and they'd rather just use those forms that they know you'll respond to.
ومن الأفضل أن يستعملوا فقط تلك الأشكال التي يعلمون أنكم ستجاوبون معها.
That's how we end up with buildings like this.
لذلك فإننا نحصل في النهاية على بنايات كهذه.
This is a nice building.
هذه بناية جميلة.
This is the Livingston Public Library
هذه هي مكتبة ليفنغستون العامة
that was completed in 2004 in my hometown,
التي تم الانتهاء منها سنة 2004 في مسقط رأسي،
and, you know, it's got a dome
ولديها، كما تعلمون، قبة
and it's got this round thing and columns, red brick,
وذلك الشيء الدائري، وبها أعمدة، وآجور أحمر،
and you can kind of guess what Livingston is trying to say with this building:
وبإمكانكم أن تخمنوا ما تحاول ليفنغستون أن تقوله من خلال هذه البناية:
children, property values and history.
الأطفال، قيم الممتلكات وتاريخها.
But it doesn't have much to do with what a library actually does today.
لكن ليست لها أوجه تشابه كثيرة مع ما تقوم به المكتبات اليوم.
That same year, in 2004, on the other side of the country,
في تلك السنة نفسها، 2004، في الجانب الآخر من البلاد،
another library was completed,
تم الانتهاء من بناء مكتبة أخرى.
and it looks like this.
كانت تبدو هكذا.
It's in Seattle.
في سياتل.
This library is about how we consume media in a digital age.
تدور فكرة هذه المكتبة عن كيفية استهلاكنا للإعلام في الزمن الرقمي.
It's about a new kind of public amenity for the city,
فهي تشكل نوعا من المناعة العمومية للمدينة،
a place to gather and read and share.
مكان للتجمع وللقراءة ولمشاركة الآراء.
So how is it possible
إذن كيف أنه من الممكن
that in the same year, in the same country,
أنه في نفس السنة، في نفس الدولة،
two buildings, both called libraries,
تبدو بنايتان، كلتاهما مكتبتان،
look so completely different?
بشكلين مختلفين تماما؟
And the answer is that architecture works on the principle of a pendulum.
والجواب أن الهندسة تعمل بمبدأ عقارب الساعة.
On the one side is innovation,
في الجهة الأولى نجد الابتكار،
and architects are constantly pushing, pushing for new technologies,
حيث يدفع المهندسون باستمرار في اتجاه تبني تكنولوجيا حديثة،
new typologies, new solutions for the way that we live today.
دراسة رموز جديدة، حلول جديدة للكيفية التي نعيش بها اليوم.
And we push and we push and we push
ذلك أننا ندفع وندفع وندفع
until we completely alienate all of you.
حتى نجعلكم تنفرون جميعا.
We wear all black, we get very depressed,
نرتدي ملابس سوداء، ونكتئب،
you think we're adorable,
فتعتقدون أننا محببون،
we're dead inside because we've got no choice.
فنموت في دواخلنا لأنه بالنهاية ليس لنا خيار آخر.
We have to go to the other side
علينا أن نتوجه إلى الجهة الأخرى
and reengage those symbols that we know you love.
لنشرك مرة أخرى تلك الرموز التي نعلم أنكم تحبونها.
So we do that, and you're happy,
نفعل هذا فتصبحون سعداء،
we feel like sellouts,
نشعر وكأنها خيانة،
so we start experimenting again
فنبدأ في الاختبار مرة أخرى
and we push the pendulum back and back and forth and back and forth
فنعيد العقرب إلى الوراء ثم إلى الأمام ونعيد الكرة
we've gone for the last 300 years,
وقد قمنا بهذا خلال 300 سنة الماضية.
and certainly for the last 30 years.
وبالتأكيد خلال ال30 سنة الماضية.
Okay, 30 years ago we were coming out of the '70s.
منذ 30 سنة مضت، كنا خرجنا للتو من السبعينات.
Architects had been busy experimenting with something called brutalism.
كان المهندسون حينها منشغلين باختبار شيء يدعى العمارة الوحشية.
It's about concrete.
أمر له صلة بالإسمنت.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You can guess this.
يمكنكم أن تخمنوا ذلك.
Small windows, dehumanizing scale.
نوافذ صغيرة، بمقاييس لاإنسانية.
This is really tough stuff.
هذا أمر صعب للغاية.
So as we get closer to the '80s,
نقترب من الثمانينات،
we start to reengage those symbols.
وبدأنا نشرك هذه الرموز.
We push the pendulum back into the other direction.
فندفع العقرب إلى الجهة الأخرى.
We take these forms that we know you love
نأخذ تلك الأشكال التي نعلم أنكم تحبونها
and we update them.
فنقوم بتحديثها.
We add neon
نضيف النيون
and we add pastels
ونضيف الباستيل
and we use new materials.
ونستعمل مواد جديدة.
And you love it.
فتحبونها.
And we can't give you enough of it.
فلا نستطيع إشباعكم بالقدر الكافي.
We take Chippendale armoires
نأخذ الخزائن الإنكليزية
and we turned those into skyscrapers,
فنحولها إلى ناطحات سحاب،
and skyscrapers can be medieval castles made out of glass.
فيمكنها أن تكون قصورا زجاجية من العصور الوسطى.
Forms got big,
كبرت الأحجام،
forms got bold and colorful.
أصبحت ملونة وأكثر حدة.
Dwarves became columns.
أصبح الأقزام بحجم الأعمدة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Swans grew to the size of buildings.
كبر البجع ليصبح بحجم المباني.
It was crazy.
كان ذلك جنونيا.
But it's the '80s, it's cool.
لكنها الثمانينيات، فالأمر إذن رائع.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We're all hanging out in malls
نلتقي جميعا في المجمعات التجارية
and we're all moving to the suburbs,
وننتقل جميعا لنعيش في الضواحي،
and out there, out in the suburbs,
وهناك، في الضواحي،
we can create our own architectural fantasies.
يمكن أن نخلق خيالات هندسية.
And those fantasies,
وهذه الخيالات
they can be Mediterranean
يمكن أن تكون متوسطية
or French
أو فرنسية
or Italian.
أو ٍإيطالية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Possibly with endless breadsticks.
ربما قد تكون لها أعواد خبزية لا متناهية.
This is the thing about postmodernism.
هذه هي فكرة ما بعد التحضر.
This is the thing about symbols.
هذه هي الفكرة التي تدور حول الرموز.
They're easy, they're cheap,
فهي سهلة، رخيصة،
because instead of making places,
لأننا عوضا عن بناء أمكنة،
we're making memories of places.
فإننا نصنع ذكريات عن الأمكنة.
Because I know, and I know all of you know,
لأنني أعلم، وأعلم أنكم جميع تعلمون،
this isn't Tuscany.
أن هذه ليست توسكاني.
This is Ohio.
بل أوهايو.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So architects get frustrated,
لذا فالمهندسون قلقون،
and we start pushing the pendulum back into the other direction.
لذلك نبدأ في إعادة عقارب الساعة إلى الجهة الأخرى.
In the late '80s and early '90s,
في نهاية الثمانينات وأوائل التسعينات،
we start experimenting with something called deconstructivism.
بدأنا باختبار ما نسميه حركة الهدم.
We throw out historical symbols,
بدأنا بإلقاء الرموز التاريخية بعيدا،
we rely on new, computer-aided design techniques,
واعتمدنا على تقنيات تصميم جديدة مدعومة بالحاسوب،
and we come up with new compositions,
وخرجنا بمجموعة من التركيبات الجديدة،
forms crashing into forms.
من حطام إلى أشكال.
This is academic and heady stuff,
هذه أمور أكاديمية وصعبة،
it's super unpopular,
وليست محبوبة تماما.
we totally alienate you.
نحن نخذلكم بشكل كبير.
Ordinarily, the pendulum would just swing back into the other direction.
عادة ما يتأرجح العقرب وحده ليعود إلى الجهة الأخرى.
And then, something amazing happened.
بعد ذلك حصل أمر رائع.
In 1997, this building opened.
سنة 1997، تم افتتاح هذا المبنى.
This is the Guggenheim Bilbao, by Frank Gehry.
هذا هو غوغنهايم بيلباو لمهندسه فرانك غيهري.
And this building
وهذا المبنى
fundamentally changes the world's relationship to architecture.
قد غير جذريا علاقة العالم بالهندسة.
Paul Goldberger said that Bilbao was one of those rare moments
قال بول غولد برجر أن بيلباو كانت واحدة من تلك العلامات الفارقة
when critics, academics, and the general public
حين يتحد النقاد والأكاديميون والعموم
were completely united around a building.
بشكل كامل بخصوص مبنى ما.
The New York Times called this building a miracle.
اعتبرت نيو يورك تايمز هذا المبنى كمعجزة.
Tourism in Bilbao increased 2,500 percent
تضاعفت السياحة في بيلباو بنسبة 2500 في المئة
after this building was completed.
بعد الانتهاء من هذا المبنى.
So all of a sudden, everybody wants one of these buildings:
فجأة، أصبح الجميع يرغب في واحدة من هذه البنايات:
L.A.,
لوس أنجلوس،
Seattle,
سياتل،
Chicago,
شيكاغو،
New York,
نيو يورك،
Cleveland,
كليفلاند،
Springfield.
سبرينغفيلد.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Everybody wants one, and Gehry is everywhere.
الكل أراد مبنى مماثلا، وأصبح غيهري يجوب كل مكان.
He is our very first starchitect.
إنه أول مهندس يصبح نجما.
Now, how is it possible that these forms --
الآن، كيف من الممكن لهذه الأشكال--
they're wild and radical --
الجامحة والتقليدية--
how is it possible that they become so ubiquitous throughout the world?
كيف يمكنها أن تكون في أرجاء العالم؟
And it happened because media so successfully galvanized around them
حصل هذا لأن الإعلام نجح جدا في
that they quickly taught us that these forms mean culture and tourism.
ليعلمنا بسرعة أن هذه الأشكال تعني الثقافة والسياحة.
We created an emotional reaction to these forms.
فخلقنا ردة فعل عاطفية اتجاه هذه الأشكال.
So did every mayor in the world.
وكذلك فعل كل عمدة مدينة في العالم.
So every mayor knew that if they had these forms,
إذ أن كل عمدة يعلم أنه إن كانت لمدينته أشكال كهذه،
they had culture and tourism.
فهي تمتلك الثقافة والسياحة.
This phenomenon at the turn of the new millennium
حصلت هذه الظاهرة مع بداية الألفية الجديدة
happened to a few other starchitects.
لبعض من المهندسين النجوم الآخرين.
It happened to Zaha
حصلت مع زاها
and it happened to Libeskind,
ليبسكايند،
and what happened to these elite few architects
وما حصل مع هذه النخبة القليلة من المهندسين
at the turn of the new millennium
مع بداية الألفية الجديدة
could actually start to happen to the entire field of architecture,
كان ليبدأ في التأثير على مجال الهندسة ككل،
as digital media starts to increase the speed
حيث بدأ الإعلام الرقمي في زيادة السرعة
with which we consume information.
التي نستهلك بها المعلومات.
Because think about how you consume architecture.
فكروا كيف أنكم تستهلكون الهندسة.
A thousand years ago,
مند 1000 سنة،
you would have had to have walked to the village next door to see a building.
كان عليكم أن تسيروا باتجاه القرية المجاورة لتروا بناية ما.
Transportation speeds up:
تزداد سرعة المواصلات:
You can take a boat, you can take a plane, you can be a tourist.
يمكنك أن تبحر في سفينة، أن تستقل طائرة، أن تكون سائحا.
Technology speeds up: You can see it in a newspaper, on TV,
تزداد سرعة التكنولوجيا: يمكن أن تراها في الجريدة، أو على التلفاز،
until finally, we are all architectural photographers,
في النهاية، كلنا مهندسون مصورون،
and the building has become disembodied from the site.
وقد تم تحرير روح البناية من الموقع
Architecture is everywhere now,
الهندسة في كل مكان الآن،
and that means that the speed of communication
وهذا ما يعني أن سرعة التواصل
has finally caught up to the speed of architecture.
قد لحقت أخيرا بسرعة الهندسة.
Because architecture actually moves quite quickly.
لأن الهندسة تتحرك بسرعة نوعا ما.
It doesn't take long to think about a building.
لا يتطلب التفكير في تصميم بناية وقتا طويلا.
It takes a long time to build a building,
بل بناؤها هو الذي يأخذ وقتا طويل،
three or four years,
ثلاث أو أربع سنوات،
and in the interim, an architect will design two or eight
وفي تلك الفترة سيصمم مهندس تصميمين أو ثمانية
or a hundred other buildings
أو مئة بناية أخرى
before they know if that building that they designed four years ago
قبل أن يعرف هل حقق المبنى الذي صممه منذ أربع سنوات
was a success or not.
نجاحا أم لا.
That's because there's never been a good feedback loop in architecture.
ذلك أنه لا توجد في الهندسة حلقة تغذية رجعية.
That's how we end up with buildings like this.
لذلك ينتهي بنا المطاف ببنايات كهذه.
Brutalism wasn't a two-year movement,
ليست حركة العمارة الوحشية وليدة سنتين فقط،
it was a 20-year movement.
فهي حركة عمرها 20 سنة.
For 20 years, we were producing buildings like this
منذ 20 سنة كنا نخرج للوجود بنايات كهذه
because we had no idea how much you hated it.
لأننا لم نكن ندري كم كنتم تكرهونها.
It's never going to happen again,
لن يحدث هذا مجددا،
I think,
على ما أعتقد،
because we are living on the verge of the greatest revolution in architecture
لأننا نعيش على حافة واحدة من أعظم الثورات الهندسية
since the invention of concrete,
منذ اختراع الإسمنت،
of steel, or of the elevator,
والحديد، أو المصعد،
and it's a media revolution.
وما صاحبه من ثورة إعلامية.
So my theory is that when you apply media to this pendulum,
إذن فنظريتي هي أنه حين تطبق الإعلام على رقاص الساعة،
it starts swinging faster and faster,
فإنه يبدأ في التحرك أسرع فأسرع،
until it's at both extremes nearly simultaneously,
حتى يصل إلى أقصى جانبيه بشكل شبه متزامن،
and that effectively blurs the difference between innovation and symbol,
وهذا بالفعل يمحق الفرق بين الإبداع والرموز،
between us, the architects, and you, the public.
بين بعضنا، بين المهندسين، بينكم، وبين العامة.
Now we can make nearly instantaneous, emotionally charged symbols
يمكننا الآن خلق رموز مشحونة عاطفيا بشكل شبه لحظي
out of something that's brand new.
من شيء جديد كليا.
Let me show you how this plays out
دعوني أريكم كيف يعمل هذا الأمر
in a project that my firm recently completed.
من خلال مشروع أنهته شركتي مؤخرا.
We were hired to replace this building, which burned down.
تم جلبنا لنعوض هذا البناء الذي هدم.
This is the center of a town called the Pines
هذا مركز مدينة تدعى "ذ باينز"
in Fire Island in New York State.
في "فاير أيلند" في ولاية نيويورك.
It's a vacation community.
هي عبارة عن تجمع سياحي.
We proposed a building that was audacious,
اقترحنا بناية تنم عن الشجاعة،
that was different than any of the forms that the community was used to,
كانت مختلفة عن كل البنايات التي تعود عليها السكان،
and we were scared and our client was scared
كنا خائفين وكان عميلنا خائفا
and the community was scared,
وكان السكان خائفون،
so we created a series of photorealistic renderings
فخلقنا سلسلة من التصورات الواقعية للإعدادات
that we put onto Facebook
ووضعناها على الفيسبوك
and we put onto Instagram,
ووضعناها على الانستغرام،
and we let people start to do what they do:
وتركنا الناس يبدؤون في فعل ما يفعلونه:
share it, comment, like it, hate it.
مشاركتها، التعليق عليها، الإعجاب بها، ومقتها.
But that meant that two years before the building was complete,
لكن هذا كان يعني أنه قبل الانتهاء من البناء بسنتين،
it was already a part of the community,
كان المبنى مسبقا جزء من المجتمع،
so that when the renderings looked exactly like the finished product,
وحين تبدو الإعدادات مطابقة تماما للمنتج النهائي،
there were no surprises.
فلن تكون هناك مفاجآت.
This building was already a part of this community,
كان هذا المبنى مسبقا جزء من المجتمع،
and then that first summer,
بعدها في أول صيف حينها،
when people started arriving and sharing the building on social media,
حين بدأ الناس بالتوافد ومشاركة صور البناء على شبكات التواصل الاجتماعي،
the building ceased to be just an edifice and it became media,
لم يعد البناء مجرد بناية بل أصبح إعلاما،
because these, these are not just pictures of a building,
لأن هذه ليست فقط مجرد صور لبناية،
they're your pictures of a building.
بل هي صوركم أنتم لهذه البناية.
And as you use them to tell your story,
وحين تستعملونها لترووا حكايتكم،
they become part of your personal narrative,
فهي تصبح جزء من سردكم،
and what you're doing is you're short-circuiting
وما تقومون به هو اختصار الطريق
all of our collective memory,
على ذاكرتنا الجماعية،
and you're making these charged symbols for us to understand.
وتخلقون هذه الرموز المشحونة عاطفية لنا لنفهمها.
That means we don't need the Greeks anymore
هذا يعني أننا لم نعد نحتاج لليونانيين
to tell us what to think about architecture.
لكي يملوا علينا ما علينا التفكير به بخصوص الهندسة.
We can tell each other what we think about architecture,
يمكن أن نخبر بعضنا البعض عما نعتقده بخصوص الهندسة،
because digital media hasn't just changed the relationship between all of us,
لأن التواصل الاجتماعي لم يغير علاقتنا ببعضنا فحسب،
it's changed the relationship between us and buildings.
بل غير أيضا العلاقة بيننا وبين البنايات.
Think for a second about those librarians back in Livingston.
فكروا للحظة في رواد المكتبة هناك في ليفنغستون.
If that building was going to be built today,
إن كان ذلك البناء سيبنى اليوم،
the first thing they would do is go online and search "new libraries."
كان أول ما سيقومون به هو الذهاب للإنترنت والبحث عن "مكتبات جديدة."
They would be bombarded by examples of experimentation, of innovation,
سيفاجؤون حينها بأمثلة عن الاختبارات، وعن الابداع،
of pushing at the envelope of what a library can be.
والتفكير بشكل أعمق عن ماهية المكتبة.
That's ammunition.
تلك هي الذخيرة.
That's ammunition that they can take with them
تلك هي الذخيرة التي يمكن أن يأخذوها معهم
to the mayor of Livingston, to the people of Livingston,
لعمدة ليفينغستون، ولسكان ليفنغستون،
and say, there's no one answer to what a library is today.
ولنقل ليس هناك تعريف واحد لماهية المكتبة اليوم.
Let's be a part of this.
ولنكن جزء من هذا.
This abundance of experimentation
تواجد التجارب بكثرة
gives them the freedom to run their own experiment.
يعطيهم الحرية لإجراء اختباراتهم.
Everything is different now.
كل شيء مختلف الآن.
Architects are no longer these mysterious creatures
لم يعد المهندسون تلك المخلوقات الغامضة
that use big words and complicated drawings,
التي تستعمل كلمات مبهمة ورسوما صعبة،
and you aren't the hapless public,
ولم تعودوا قط ذلك الجمهور المغلوب على أمره،
the consumer that won't accept anything that they haven't seen anymore.
ذلك الزبون الذي لن يقبل شيئا لم يره من قبل.
Architects can hear you,
المهندسون ينصتون لكم،
and you're not intimidated by architecture.
ولستم تخافون الهندسة
That means that that pendulum swinging back and forth
هذا يعني أن رقاص الساعة الذي يتأرجح إلى الأمام وإلى الخلف
from style to style, from movement to movement,
من طريقة إلى أخرى، من حركة الى أخرى،
is irrelevant.
لم يعد له أي معنى.
We can actually move forward
يمكننا أن نتحرك نحو الأمام
and find relevant solutions to the problems that our society faces.
ونجد حلولا قيمة للمشاكل التي يواجهها مجتمعنا.
This is the end of architectural history,
هذه هي نهاية تاريخ الهندسة،
and it means that the buildings of tomorrow
وهذا يعني أن بنايات الغد
are going to look a lot different than the buildings of today.
ستبدو مختلفة كثيرا عن بنايات اليوم.
It means that a public space in the ancient city of Seville
ما يعني أن المساحات العامة في المدينة القديمة لإشبيلية
can be unique and tailored to the way that a modern city works.
يمكنها أن تكون فريدة ومصممة على النحو الذي تعمل به مدينة حديثة.
It means that a stadium in Brooklyn can be a stadium in Brooklyn,
ما يعني أن ملعبا في بروكلين يمكن أن يكون ملعبا هناك،
not some red-brick historical pastiche
لا أن يكون تقليدا تاريخيا ذا آجور أحمر
of what we think a stadium ought to be.
كما نعتقد أن يكون عليه ملعب ما.
It means that robots are going to build our buildings,
هذا يعني أن الروبوتات ستبني أبنيتنا،
because we're finally ready for the forms that they're going to produce.
لأننا أخيرا مستعدون لاستيعاب الأشكال التي ستنتجها.
And it means that buildings will twist to the whims of nature
هذا يعني أيضا أن الأبنية ستتمايل مع أهواء الطبيعة
instead of the other way around.
وليس العكس.
It means that a parking garage in Miami Beach, Florida,
هذا يعني أن مرأب سيارات في ميامي بيتش في فلوريدا،
can also be a place for sports
يمكنه أن يكون مكانا للرياضة
and for yoga
ولليوغا
and you can even get married there late at night.
ويمكنكم أيضا أن تتزوجوا هناك في وقت متأخر من الليل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It means that three architects can dream about swimming
هذا يعني أن يحلم ثلاثة مهندسين بالسباحة
in the East River of New York,
في النهر الشرقي في نيويورك،
and then raise nearly half a million dollars
فيجمعون ما يقارب نصف مليون دولار
from a community that gathered around their cause,
من الناس الذين تجمعوا حول قضيتهم،
no one client anymore.
لم يعد لديهم حتى زبون واحد.
It means that no building is too small for innovation,
هذا يعني أنه لا بناية قط أصغر من أن يبدع فيها،
like this little reindeer pavilion
كجناح الأيل الصغير هذا
that's as muscly and sinewy as the animals it's designed to observe.
فهو قوي ووتري كتلك الحيوانات التي صمم لمراقبتها.
And it means that a building doesn't have to be beautiful
وهذا يعني ألا يجب على بناية ما أن تكون جميلة
to be lovable,
لكي تكون محبوبة،
like this ugly little building in Spain,
كهذه البناية الصغيرة القبيحة في اسبانيا،
where the architects dug a hole,
حيث حفر المهندسون حفرة،
packed it with hay,
وملؤوها بالقش.
and then poured concrete around it,
وأفرغوا الإسمنت حولها،
and when the concrete dried,
وحين جف الإسمنت،
they invited someone to come and clean that hay out
دعوا أحدهم ليأتي وينظف القش
so that all that's left when it's done
حتى لا يتبقى منه
is this hideous little room
إلا هذه الغرفة الصغيرة الخفية
that's filled with the imprints and scratches of how that place was made,
المليئة بالبقايا والخربشات التي تنم عما صنع منه هذا المكان،
and that becomes the most sublime place to watch a Spanish sunset.
والذي أصبح واحدا من أكثر الأماكن سحرا لمشاهدة الغروب الإسباني.
Because it doesn't matter if a cow builds our buildings
لأنه لا يهم إن كانت بقرة هي من بنت بناياتنا
or a robot builds our buildings.
أو روبوت من بناها.
It doesn't matter how we build, it matters what we build.
لا يهم كيف نبني، ما يهم هو ما نبنيه.
Architects already know how to make buildings that are greener
يعرف المهندسون مسبقا كيف يبنون بنايات صديقة للبيئة
and smarter and friendlier.
أكثر ذكاء وأسهل في الاستخدام.
We've just been waiting for all of you to want them.
كنا فقط ننتظركم جميعا أن تعجبوا بها.
And finally, we're not on opposite sides anymore.
وأخيرا، لم نعد قط على الجهة المقابلة.
Find an architect, hire an architect,
جد مهندسا، استعمل مهندسا،
work with us to design better buildings, better cities, and a better world,
اعمل معنا لنصمم بنايات أفضل، مدنا أفضل، وعالما أفضل.
because the stakes are high.
لأن المعايير عالية.
Buildings don't just reflect our society, they shape our society
لا تعكس البنايات مجتمعنا، بل تحدد معالمه
down to the smallest spaces:
من خلال أبسط الفضاءات:
the local libraries,
المكتبات المحلية،
the homes where we raise our children,
المنازل التي نربي فيها أطفالنا،
and the walk that they take from the bedroom to the bathroom.
والممر الذي يأخذونه من غرفة النوم إلى الحمام.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)